<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>propiro.github.io</title>
    <link href="https://propiro.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://propiro.github.io" />
    <updated>2020-01-10T14:19:07+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>piro</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://propiro.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Dualscreen (for now) Thinkpad prototype</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/dualscreen-for-now-thinkpad-prototype.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/dualscreen-for-now-thinkpad-prototype.html</id>

        <updated>2020-01-10T14:18:55+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hello, For quite a long time i wanted a dualscreen laptop. While im aware of existence of few constructions, they're either old or super-expensive - and i like my thinkpad due to its... expendability. Since i've aquired a resin printer, i've decided to try and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Hello,</p>
<p>For quite a long time i wanted a dualscreen laptop. While im aware of existence of few constructions, they're either old or super-expensive - and i like my thinkpad due to its... expendability.</p>
<p>Since i've aquired a resin printer, i've decided to try and make one on the cheap, and after a sleepless nigt, a prototype model was made:</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/ezgif-3-e57c1cf05620.gif" alt="" width="600" height="501"></p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/ezgif-3-ec0c720ba786.gif" alt="" width="600" height="501"></p>
<p> </p>
<p>and printed prototype can be seen here, mounted to... deasembled upper part of another thinkpad frame, housing an FHD screen matrix:</p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_13h59_49.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_13h59_49-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="652" height="856"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_13h59_56.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_13h59_56-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="634" height="341"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_14h00_03.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/17/gallery/2020-01-10_14h00_03-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="617" height="823"></a></figure>
</div>
<p>Controller is salvaged from broken USB FHD screen, still need to figure out how to guide cables in not annoying way, as well remove the hinges from top screen and print some covers/caps for the hole that'll be there. And of course replace the zip-ties with metal pins, I have a special bearings ordered already (so its not metal and resing connection that'll worn off quickly), just waiting for everything to be sent.</p>
<p>HEY, ITS SOMETHING!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Pi zero inside Multibay, part 2: I dont even.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/pi-zero-inside-multibay-part-2-i-dont-even.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/pi-zero-inside-multibay-part-2-i-dont-even.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-21T22:39:55+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you follow for some reason my posts, i've been struggling with getting juice out of SATA slimline connector to power raspberry pi, that was to be put inside Thinkpads ultrabay. And I've made it work. And realised I've lost ultrabay space. In addition, fooling&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>If you follow for some reason my<a href="https://propiro.github.io/getting-juice-out-of-laptop-satamsata-connector-to-power-up-things.html"> posts</a>, i've been struggling with <a href="https://propiro.github.io/getting-juice-out-of-laptop-satamsata-connector-to-power-up-things.html">getting juice out of SATA slimline connector</a> to power raspberry pi, that was to be put inside Thinkpads ultrabay.</p>
<p>And I've made it work.</p>
<p>And realised I've lost ultrabay space. In addition, fooling the ultrabay connector that SOMETHING is connected to id made my thinkpad beep at start with warning that it cannot detect the drive.</p>
<p>So, naturally, I've decided NOT to allow any compromises, because they're sign of weakness, and have both things alltogether.</p>
<p>DID YOU KNOW SATA DRIVES DONT NEED TO TAKE ALL THE SPACE IN 2.5 ENCLOSURE?</p>
<p>Some shots of work in progress: </p>
<div class="gallery"   >
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_03.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_03-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="615" height="823"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Power lines soldered to ssd pcb, this was most intrusive point where something could go wrong.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_16.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_16-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="613" height="824"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Cables secured with tape.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_26.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_26-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="611" height="821"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">SSD Pcb overlayed on top of PI Zero PCB, cables soldered, not arranged.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_36.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_36-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="613" height="822"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Added DIP-switch to have some control when I want it On or OFF, in case i want to safe on battery.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_48.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_48-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="617" height="821"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">The whole DIP switch wasnt neccessary, but i wanted to troll people showing them this image and telling them it overclocks the drive.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_58.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h56_58-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="610" height="822"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Looks cool, all ports accessible, there is plenty of space for small accessories in ultrabay to connect (like external receivers / pendrives)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h57_10.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h57_10-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="610" height="817"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Different shot</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h57_18.png" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/16/gallery/2019-12-18_11h57_18-thumbnail.png" alt="" width="768" height="372"></a>
<figcaption class="gallery-description">Mounted in ultrabay, unless someone eject it from laptop, there is no change of guessing there is computer inside computer.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Things i'll add to it, because its not pointless enough:</p>
<p>Small accumulator to make it run for several minutes between restarts of laptop.</p>
<p>OLED screen to display (outside of the thinkpad bay, will require some dremel work) IP adress and uptime/network usage</p>
<p>WIRED two-way of communication between thinkpad (i use windows on my laptops) and pi zero, probably will require adding some internal cables with USB lines. So it could act as an another usb drive OR input device controlled from... anything that can SSH into it.</p>
<p>At some point of making this mod, someone asked me why. I've never asked this myself, at some point I just wanted to do it to be sure I can.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>OK BOOMER 3D Workflow, it works.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/ok-boomer-3d-workflow-it-works.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/ok-boomer-3d-workflow-it-works.html</id>

        <updated>2019-12-18T11:42:25+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Several people asked me about my workflow, so I've decided to put it here for easy of access. This is translation of one of 2010-something post i've made on max3d.pl, with additions to workflow with techniques / tools that are more recent. My current modelling&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                Several people asked me about my workflow, so I've decided to put it here for easy of access. This is translation of one of 2010-something post i've made on max3d.pl, with additions to workflow with techniques / tools that are more recent.<br><br>My current modelling workflow include softwares:<br><br><a href="https://www.pureref.com/">pureref </a>- working with references<br><a href="https://www.autodesk.pl/products/3ds-max/overview">3ds max</a> - base /lp/hp modelling - get <a href="http://renderhjs.net/textools/3dsMax.html">textools</a> maxscript for it and install.<br><a href="https://www.autodesk.pl/products/3ds-max/overview">uv layout</a> - tight unwraps<br><a href="https://marmoset.co/toolbag/">marmoset</a> - baking<br><br><br><br>You can make most of these things just in 3ds max like I did in the dinosaur times, and I'll write up when you can use alternatives, but this post will be focused on using above packages.<br><br>My lowpoly (LP from now on) models are created 100% in 3D studio max, version 2012 that I've bought licence for many sheckels, or 2017, that one of my favorite clients generously bought for me. Most of my custom tools that help me speed up my workflow are in 2012 though, and i dont use any particular features that are NOT in 2012 that'd force me to use newer version. Why I'm not upgrading? Because subscription model, at least by the time of writing this post, is quite expensive, and after 3 years I'd spent same money I've spent on 2012, and its almost 2020, so I'd lose triple amount of money. Anyway.<br>Assuming you have all the refs you need and few more, start modelling:<br>Blockout phase, LP phase are done in 3DS Max. Blockout phase, sometimes called "basemesh" phase when it's quite dense, but doesnt have clean topology, I'm trying to keep it in quads anyway for easier of work later. Looptool/Swift loop is your friend, when you'll be making edges around the borders to protect them when you sub-d later.<br><br>Having a basemesh that have well defined details that I'd see on LP geometry, and have a proportions that match the references / desired model, I'm making a copy of it and start working on high poly (HP from now). I use sub-d modelling exclusively, nowadays workflows like to include zbrush/dynamesh/proboolean workflow, its ok when the time is tight and you need to quickly have some results. However, it teaches practically nothing about controlling topology and flow of the geometry, so a good practice is to use sub-d whenever you can, and only half-ass meshes in zbrush when youre in a hurry and client dont care.<br><br>Ok, now that half of the people got offended and stopped reading, the HP I end up with have all the details on geometry, with the exceptions like diamond patterns on grips or fabric weave that can be easily made on texture itself. I do model sometimes braided cables / more complex diamond patterns when the surface they're on is curved, but its usually pain.<br><br>With HP done, I go back to my basemesh, that now should overlap with the finished high poly pretty tight. Duplicating it, this will be my low-poly mesh. Im deleting uneccessary edges / division, making the basemesh truly lowpoly, yet detailed enough to bake properly (rules for certain types of objects still apply - where to put denser geo, what chamfer and what not, depending on where the camera looks, et cetera). Now the magical part that streamlines unwrapping by 80% of time. I set up automatic smoothgroups by 33-45degrees, having most if not all hard edges well defined on low poly, The i apply unwrap UVW modifier, and use one nifty function - uv chunks by smoothgroups, that creates uv islands based off your smoothgroups. Only thing you need to manually cut are cylinders, that need to be cut on one edge to unwrap properly. After all the pieces are done, I use quick peel, relax, and have quite good, relaxed UVs. <br><br><em>The poor mans UV version, using 3ds max:</em><br><em>Ok, now you'll need some automation, unless you want/need to do tis by hand. Get a copy of textools, and on previously prepared uv pieces run "Sort" (to get all the UV pieces alignes to one of axes, this is important step) and then "Pack" or whatever it is called. Remember to:</em><br><em>- turn off any snapping in 3ds max, or you'll end up with weirdly rotated pieces instead of nicely arranged, vertically/horisontally oriented UVs </em><br><em>- have some padding options, you dont want to have zero-pixel distances between the uv islands, it'll cause bleeding and baking issues later.</em><br><br>This is less efficient way and gives a rather random result, but if you'll be using painter to texture it, it doesnt matter that much how logically arranged the UVs are, as you';; be using viewport to texture it anyway.<br><br>Normal UV version, using UV layout:<br>I scale UVs in max, depending on their importance (back/bottom faces are smaller, sights are larger, etc). Such prepared model is going to UV layout (strongly advice getting the "UV layour bridge" script for super-fast work between max and UV layout)<br>In uv layout, I make few boxes around parts of certain areas, not beign very precise about it - usually for weapon I like having sights and magazine / ammo somewhere in one part of the texture, rest is scattered around 0-1 UV space.<br>Then, UV layout settings:<br>After aligning the pieces to one of the axes:<br>4k map,quality: best, bleed (padding) 12PX, 10-12MINS, no rotation, show shell bleeds, show tile coverage (very usefull for dick comparing later that you've utilised the UV better than rest of the people), Allow box overlaps, shrink boxes to fit. Rest by default, usually 1 or off.<br>Click pack, go make a coffe, return 10 minutes later, and enjoy having model packed more tightly than you'd ever managed to pack by hand. Or click again and test results, its up to you. For more complex morels, 15 minutes of UV layout work could save me up to 10hours of packing. <br>After everything, click "send" if you're using UV bridge, or save the mapped obj and get it back to max.<br><br>When you have the model back in max, run on it a textool function "Smoothing groups from UV chunks" - this is to endure that my smoothgroups are still synced with uv islands. Now, into the baking.<br><br><em>The poor mans baking version, using 3ds max:</em><br><em>Note that you wont be getting all the nice maps that substance painter uses, thats the main reason i've started using marmoset baker.</em><br><em>Contrary to popular belief, you can get good normalmaps from 3ds max, it just require some more knowledge and work, that most people dont have or want to pursue. Anyway:</em><br><em>On your lowpoly model, apply "Turn to poly" modifier, and limit the edges to 3. This will make your model triangulated, without making any permanent modifications to it. Some edges might be incorrectly placed after that, fix it on edit_poly modifier using "turn" option for faces edges.</em><br><em>Apply Projection modifier on top of it, add your HP meshes, reset cage to average all verticles of it, and offset it. Spend some time manually tweaking it (shouldnt take more than 5 minutes) next step.</em><br><em>Render to texture dialog, an old friend for old people. Bake normalmaps there with double the final resolution, to fight crappy filtering (if you start playing with filtering/aa options in render settings, it'll render longer than just double size, so do yourself a favor and save time). You should be able to bake normalmap, AO and colormap ID. Cavity map can be extracted from normalmap in photoshop using xnormal plugin. Note that sometimes you'll need to explode the model to avoig crappy overlaps from misshits of rays. Textools might help you get some additional maps.</em><br><br>Normal baking version, using marmoset toolbag.<br>Very streamlined: click on bread icon, become breadmaster.<br>Export your hp model with some iterations on sub-d (2 is usually enough, 3 if you started with super-lowpoly mesh for sub-d) - this is good moment to apply some colors to HP parts, that will be baked into material ID map, export your lp model.<br>Put highpoly meshes into HIGH group, lowpoly mesh to LOW group, Name the baked maps, tweak skew, tweak offset, select maps you need (for painter you'd want everything, especially thisckness / cavity that you wont get from max. <br>Bake it at 2x desired resolution, shrink them afterward using some sharp interpolation alghoritm.<br><br>And thats it, you have baked mesh. Most of things mentioned here are pretty straightforward, but people still ask about certain steps of creating models, so.<br>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Proper way to learn 3D.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/proper-way-to-learn-3d.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/proper-way-to-learn-3d.html</id>

        <updated>2019-10-28T14:40:35+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    So, you just finished a grenade tutorial, ak tutorial, pistol or knife one. You have zero experience in 3d modelling, but by extensive handholding you managed to finish it, clicking exactly what tutor clicked and doing exactly tutor in the movie did. You learned nothing.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>So, you just finished a grenade tutorial, ak tutorial, pistol or knife one. You have zero experience in 3d modelling, but by extensive handholding you managed to finish it, clicking exactly what tutor clicked and doing exactly tutor in the movie did. </p>
<p>You learned nothing. Instead of writing a book using your own words, you've just copied the whole thing from someone else, not really learning anything, just followed the guides. Gained very little. Now youre asking where is the insed function. Or why extrude is making weird lines. Or where the selection thingy go, and what its named. Or similiar, basic question.</p>
<p>Learning 3D (not 3d, anything in reality) is lenghty process. It takes months, even years to be reasonably good with it. It is boring as well, done the proper way, that will benefit you later. Due to availability of videotutorials and widespread internet access, where everyone can now "teach", its very easy to fall into a trap of being fooled about your own skills, by people who dont posses them on a level that'd allow them to evaluate your own.</p>
<p>To avoid mistakes like these, you should take the boring way. Most, if  not all softwares, have quite good help files/manuals, either online or under universal, often ignored F1 key. Most of your questions are answered there, you just need to search them. Here are few links to help docs for certain softwares:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>3D Studio Max: <a href="http://help.autodesk.com/view/3DSMAX/2019/ENU/">http://help.autodesk.com/view/3DSMAX/2019/ENU/</a></p>
<p>Maya: <a href="https://help.autodesk.com/view/MAYAUL/2019/ENU/">https://help.autodesk.com/view/MAYAUL/2019/ENU/</a></p>
<p>Zbrush: <a href="http://docs.pixologic.com/">http://docs.pixologic.com/</a></p>
<p>Blender: <a href="https://docs.blender.org/manual/en/latest/">https://docs.blender.org/manual/en/latest/</a></p>
<p>Modo: <a href="https://learn.foundry.com/modo/content/help/pages/learn.html">https://learn.foundry.com/modo/content/help/pages/learn.html</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>If youre total beginner with the program, start with reading up the "getting started / basic / introduction" etc chapters, where everything is explained in a very simple way. Build your knowledge on top of it. Experiment with every function/tool on some simple shapes until you know what it does. After you go through all the explanatory chapters, and are comfortable with interface and tools available, then pick up a more complex tutorial, never before.</p>
<p>Good luck.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Most common mistakes while making 3d asset.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/most-common-mistakes-while-making-3d-asset.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/most-common-mistakes-while-making-3d-asset.html</id>

        <updated>2019-09-05T15:39:48+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    And how to avoid them, minimising the damage. If your model have issues, you most likely messed up some step or steps. Enjoy re-doing most of your work. Click here for explanation: ASSET CREATION GRAPH + EXPLANATION 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>And how to avoid them, minimising the damage. If your model have issues, you most likely messed up some step or steps. Enjoy re-doing most of your work.</p>
<p>Click here for explanation: <a href="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/1nmw99LDC6LnYAnZbNP67qj68Kxsug_XEBvtQX_qHJUs/edit?usp=sharing">ASSET CREATION GRAPH + EXPLANATION</a></p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/13/2019-09-05_15h39_03.png" alt="" width="365" height="1659"></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>IM  Copypasta</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/im-copypasta.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/im-copypasta.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-29T13:48:47+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Taken from: https://github.com/propiro/instantMessengersPasta To be used when someone mentions change of currently used messenging application. We could always use Skype.Or Riot or MatrixOr NextCloudOr XMPPOr WireOr BriarOr ToxOr KontalkOr DeltaChatOr RingOr BitMessageOr RicochetOr PSYC2Or RocketOr IRCOr MattermostOr ZulipOr OrbitOr MumblOr SpectrumOr SignalOr KeybaseOr SureSpotOr SilenceOr&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="align-center">Taken from: <a href="https://github.com/propiro/instantMessengersPasta" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/propiro/instantMessengersPasta</a></p>
<p>To be used when someone mentions change of currently used messenging application.</p>
<p><code></code></p>
<pre>We could always use Skype.
Or Riot or Matrix
Or NextCloud
Or XMPP
Or Wire
Or Briar
Or Tox
Or Kontalk
Or DeltaChat
Or Ring
Or BitMessage
Or Ricochet
Or PSYC2
Or Rocket
Or IRC
Or Mattermost
Or Zulip
Or Orbit
Or Mumbl
Or Spectrum
Or Signal
Or Keybase
Or SureSpot
Or Silence
Or Telegram like we do now
Or IMS
Or Discord
Or Glitter
Or Duo
Or Keeperchat
Or Wirck
Or Threem
Or Whatsapp
Or Imessage
Or MSTeams
Or Facetime
Or Line
Or Allo
Or iMessenge
Or Skype
Or Hangouts
Or Reddit Chat 
Or Twitch
Or Zoom
Or Slack
Or Instagram
Or Snapchat
Or Steam
Or WeChat
Or Kik
Or Viber
Or BBM
Or Kakaotalk
Or IMO
Or QQ
Or Zalo
Or Tango
Or Tuenti
Or ICQ
Or Gadugadu
Or Pond
Or SINC
Or PSYC1
Or Zephyr
Or AIM
Or MSN
Or Yahoo Talk
Or ooVoo
Or Echo
Or cdc.io
Or Pidgen
Or GroupMe
Or Deltachat
Or Zello
Or Conpherence
Or Teamspeak
Or Hipchat
Or Rivchat
Or Die With Me


Or we could just use SMS or MMS.</pre>
<p><code></code></p>
<p> </p>
<iframe width="760" height="760" src="https://github.com/propiro/instantMessengersPasta/blob/master/pasta_en.txt"> </iframe>
<p class="align-center"> </p>
<p class="align-center"> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MACROSCRIPT: Move/Scale uv chunks by value</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/macroscript-movescale-uv-chunks-by-value.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/macroscript-movescale-uv-chunks-by-value.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-20T19:37:36+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Maxscript I wrote to help myself packing all the atlases from various textures, working on envirnoment jobs. Allows you to easily scale / move uv chunks / groups of them by defined values by clicking a D-PAD like controls. You need to have your UV&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Maxscript I wrote  to help myself packing all the atlases from various textures, working on envirnoment jobs. Allows you to easily scale / move uv chunks / groups of them by defined values by clicking a D-PAD like controls. You need to have your UV islands selected for it to work.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/11/2019-08-20_19h35_46.png" alt="" width="206" height="401">
<figcaption ></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A big one:</p>
<p><code>macroScript scaleUV</code><br><code> category:"_Piro_Tools"</code><br><code> toolTip:"UV: Scale UVs"</code><br><code> buttonText:"Scale UVs"</code><br><code>(</code><br><code> try(destroyDialog rolloutScaleUV )catch()</code><br><code> global scaleToUse = 100</code><br><code> global moveX = 1.5</code><br><code> global moveY = 1.5</code><br><code> global scaleMod = 1</code><br><code> --global scaleFN = 1</code><br><code> fn scaleUV scaleFN howScale=</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> if classof (modPanel.getCurrentObject()) == Unwrap_UVW do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> try</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> undo "Scale UVWs" on</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> if (howScale == 1) then</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> $.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap2.ScaleSelectedXY scaleFN scaleFN [0,0,0]</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> else if (howScale == 2) then</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> $.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap2.ScaleSelectedXY scaleFN 1 [0,0,0]</code><br><code> ) </code><br><code> else if (howScale == 3) then</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> $.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap2.ScaleSelectedXY 1 scaleFN [0,0,0]</code><br><code> ) </code><br> <br><code> --selection[1].unwrap_uvw.unwrap2.ScaleSelectedCenter (spnPercent.value/100.0) (rdoAxis.state-1)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> catch</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> messageBox "An unwrap modifier must be the active selection." title:"Didn't Work"</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> fn moveXfunction moveXFN =</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> if classof (modPanel.getCurrentObject()) == Unwrap_UVW do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> try</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> undo "Scale UVWs" on</code><br><code> ( </code><br><code> print "inside moving function"</code><br> <br><code> --$.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap4.SetRelativeTypeIn off</code><br><code> $.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap2.moveSelected [moveXFN,0,0]</code><br><code> --selection[1].unwrap_uvw.unwrap2.ScaleSelectedCenter (spnPercent.value/100.0) (rdoAxis.state-1)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> catch</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> messageBox "An unwrap modifier must be the active selection." title:"Didn't Work"</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> fn moveYfunction moveYFN =</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> if classof (modPanel.getCurrentObject()) == Unwrap_UVW do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> try</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> undo "Scale UVWs" on</code><br><code> ( </code><br><code> print "inside moving function"</code><br> <br><code> --$.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap4.SetRelativeTypeIn off</code><br><code> $.modifiers[#unwrap_uvw].unwrap2.moveSelected [0,moveYFN,0]</code><br><code> --selection[1].unwrap_uvw.unwrap2.ScaleSelectedCenter (spnPercent.value/100.0) (rdoAxis.state-1)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> catch</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> messageBox "An unwrap modifier must be the active selection." title:"Didn't Work"</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br> <br> <br><code> rollout rolloutScaleUV "Scale UVs" width: 170 </code><br><code> (</code><br> <br> <br> <br><code> spinner spnPercentA "Percent: " range:[-999,999,50] pos:[10,10]</code><br><code> spinner spnPercentB "Percent: " range:[-999,999,25] pos:[10,30]</code><br><code> spinner spnPercentC "Percent: " range:[-999,999,200] pos:[10,50]</code><br><code> radioButtons rdoAxis "" labels:#("XY","X","Y") default:1 offset:[0,40] pos:[25,70]</code><br><code> button btnScale1 "Scale A" pos:[5,90]</code><br><code> button btnScale2 "Scale B" pos:[55,90]</code><br><code> button btnScale3 "Scale C" pos:[105,90]</code><br><code> spinner spnMoveX "Move tile: " range:[-99,99,0.5] pos:[20,125]</code><br><code> spinner spnMoveY "Move tile: " range:[-99,99,0.5] pos:[20,145]</code><br><code> button moveUp "UP" width:50 height:50 pos:[60, 180]</code><br><code> button moveLeft "LEFT" width:50 height:50 pos:[10, 230]</code><br><code> button moveRight "RIGHT" width:50 height:50 pos:[110, 230]</code><br><code> button moveDown "DOWN" width:50 height:50 pos:[60, 280]</code><br><code> label label1 "..."</code><br> <br> <br><code> on btnScale1 pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> scaleMod = rdoAxis.state</code><br><code>scaleToUse = spnPercentA.value / 100.0</code><br><code> scaleUV scaleToUse scaleMod </code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> on btnScale2 pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> scaleMod = rdoAxis.state</code><br><code>scaleToUse = spnPercentB.value / 100.0</code><br><code> scaleUV scaleToUse scaleMod </code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> on btnScale3 pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> scaleMod = rdoAxis.state</code><br><code>scaleToUse = spnPercentC.value / 100.0</code><br><code> scaleUV scaleToUse scaleMod </code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> on moveLeft pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> print "MovingLeft"</code><br><code>moveX = (spnMoveX.value * -1.0)</code><br><code> moveXfunction(moveX)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> on moveRight pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> print "MovingRight"</code><br><code>moveX = (spnMoveX.value * 1.0)</code><br><code> moveXfunction(moveX)</code><br><code> )</code><br> <br><code> on moveUp pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> print "MovingLeft"</code><br><code>moveY = (spnMoveY.value * 1.0)</code><br><code> moveYfunction(moveY)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> on moveDown pressed do</code><br><code> (</code><br><code> print "MovingRight"</code><br><code>moveY = (spnMoveY.value * -1.0)</code><br><code> moveYfunction(moveY)</code><br><code> )</code><br><code> )</code><br><br><code> createDialog rolloutScaleUV</code><br><code>)</code></p>
<p> </p>
<p>As always, you'll find it here:</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/11/2019-08-20_19h21_19.png" alt="" width="402" height="123"></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MAXSCRIPT: Change the UVW Unwrap checker size on the fly.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-change-the-uvw-unwrap-checker-size-on-the-fly.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-change-the-uvw-unwrap-checker-size-on-the-fly.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-30T14:37:32+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Script that does something noone thinks about unless needed - adjusts size (or tiling if you wish) of checker board from UVW Unwrap modifier window (so it doesnt touch your material tiling, and checker vanishes after you exit UWV Modifier) Includes two macros, one for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Script that does something noone thinks about unless needed - adjusts size (or tiling if you wish) of checker board from UVW Unwrap modifier window (so it doesnt touch your material tiling, and checker vanishes after you exit UWV Modifier)</p>
<p>Includes two macros, one for enlarging one for shrinking the tiling value:</p>
<p><code>macroScript Chkr_plus category:"_Piro_Tools" tooltip:"+" </code><br><code>(</code><br><code> chkCoords = selection[1].unwrap_uvw.checkermaterial.diffusemap.coords</code><br><code> chkCoords.u_tiling = chkCoords.u_tiling + 1</code><br><code> chkCoords.v_tiling = chkCoords.v_tiling + 1</code><br><code>)</code></p>
<p><code>macroScript Chkr_minus category:"_Piro_Tools" tooltip:"-" </code><br><code>(</code><br><code> chkCoords = selection[1].unwrap_uvw.checkermaterial.diffusemap.coords</code><br><code> chkCoords.u_tiling = chkCoords.u_tiling - 1</code><br><code> chkCoords.v_tiling = chkCoords.v_tiling - 1</code><br><code>)</code></p>
<p> </p>
<p>As always, find it under:</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/10/2019-08-20_19h21_19.png" alt="" width="402" height="123"></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MAXSCRIPT: Centering pivot on selected object.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-centering-pivot-on-selected-object.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-centering-pivot-on-selected-object.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-20T19:25:58+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Small, very simple script that saves me few clicks: macroScript centerPivot Category:"_Piro_Tools" toolTip:"Center Pivot" ( $.pivot = $.center ) Centers the object pivot to geometry-weighted center, especially usefull when you duplicate mesh elements using shift+drag method. Found again here: Bind it to key, quad or toolbar as&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Small, very simple script that saves me few clicks:</p>
<p><code>macroScript centerPivot Category:"_Piro_Tools" toolTip:"Center Pivot"</code><br><code>(</code><br><code> $.pivot = $.center</code><br><code>)</code></p>
<p>Centers the object pivot to geometry-weighted center, especially usefull when you duplicate mesh elements using shift+drag method.</p>
<p>Found again here:</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/9/2019-08-20_19h21_19.png" alt="" width="402" height="123"></p>
<p>Bind it to key, quad or toolbar as you wish.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MAXSCRIPT: Copy &amp; Paste files between max instances and scenes</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-copy-and-paste-files-between-max-instances-and-scenes.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/maxscript-copy-and-paste-files-between-max-instances-and-scenes.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-20T19:22:41+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Two small maxscript macros that let you copy and paste files using a temporary file created in $autoback directory. macroScript Copy_Objects_To_File Category:"_Piro_Tools" toolTip:"CopyToFile" ( thecopypastedir = getdir #autoback thecopypastefile = "\pastefile.max" thecopypastestring = thecopypastedir + thecopypastefile if $ != undefined do saveNodes $ thecopypastestring )&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Two small maxscript macros that let you copy and paste files using a temporary file created in $autoback directory.</p>
<p><code>macroScript Copy_Objects_To_File Category:"_Piro_Tools" toolTip:"CopyToFile"<br>(<br> thecopypastedir = getdir #autoback <br> thecopypastefile = "\pastefile.max" <br> thecopypastestring = thecopypastedir + thecopypastefile <br> <br> if $ != undefined do <br> saveNodes $ thecopypastestring <br>)<br><br>macroScript Paste_Objects_From_File Category:"_Piro_Tools" toolTip:"PasteFromFile"<br>(<br> thecopypastedir = getdir #autoback -- folder kopiowania<br> thecopypastefile = "\pastefile.max" --nazwa dla pliku...<br> thecopypastestring = thecopypastedir + thecopypastefile --string dla funkcji kopiowania<br><br> mergemaxfile (thecopypastedir + thecopypastefile) #select -- merge of pasted objects<br>)</code></p>
<p>Save the file as something.ms, run it inside max through maxscript -&gt; run script (or drag n drop if you're administrator), you'll find the two macros here:</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/8/2019-08-20_19h21_19.png" alt="" width="402" height="123"></p>
<p>Assign them to shortcut, button or quad (im using quad menu for that), enjoy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
