<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>propiro.github.io</title>
    <link href="https://propiro.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://propiro.github.io" />
    <updated>2019-08-19T23:22:03+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>piro</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://propiro.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Fresh Artists Portfolio Tips</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/fresh-artists-portfolio-tips.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/fresh-artists-portfolio-tips.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-19T23:21:44+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Or rather, tip. Just one, at least in this post. Portfolio is equivalent of your shop front, you put only things that someone would want to buy, and you want to sell - That beign said, your best skills. Never, ever, post things that are&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Or rather, tip. Just one, at least in this post.</p>
<p>Portfolio is equivalent of your shop front, you put only things that someone would want to buy, and you want to sell - That beign said, your best skills. Never, ever, post things that are "so-so", with bunch of excuses about how quickly you did it or that your favorite cat puked on the carpet and thats why roughness is sRGB and solidcolor. These things belong to your journal / blog ( look at me, im ranting here, not on my artstation page! ), not on your portfolio, that you'll sent to potential employer, and people who are looking for possibly best artist out there.</p>
<p>Always post things that are best representation of your skill, and good idea is to seek feedback before going public. There is a lot of forums and discords, you can always ask there - probably response wont be nice and fluffy, but at least you'll get a feedback about what to change where. Take it, improve, repeat. And after a year or two, when you see improvement, its good idea to purge some old works - keep a copy on your HDD or e-mail, but don't show old stuff that fail to impress even you at this point. </p>
<p><em>Portfolio is your shop front, with best items. Not your journal where you put a tutorial piece that youre proud of, because someone hand-holded you through 20hours of video.</em></p>
<p>Or post any shit you want, I don't care. Just remember that it takes recruiter around 6 seconds of looking at portfolio before they decide if they want to click on next image or close the browser tab, because something caused them eyebleeding.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Duning - Kruger effect, AKA why people think they have superpowers and can bend time.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/duning-kruger-effect-aka-why-people-think-they-have-superpowers-and-can-bend-time.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/duning-kruger-effect-aka-why-people-think-they-have-superpowers-and-can-bend-time.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-19T22:39:45+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Take a look at this graph. This is perfect explanation on why I hear a lot of very young people, starting in industry ( Gamedev here, but applies to many other areas of life/business ), either evaluating work for impossible low hour-budgets, or taking waaay to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><img src="https://graphpaperdiaries.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/dunning-kruger-chart.jpg" alt="Znalezione obrazy dla zapytania dunning kruger graph"></p>
<p>Take a look at this graph. This is perfect explanation on why I hear a lot of very young people, starting in industry ( Gamedev here, but applies to many other areas of life/business ), either evaluating work for impossible low hour-budgets, or taking waaay to complex tasks on themselves, only to fail miserably.</p>
<p><em>It's very hard for people to evaluate something correctly, even their own experience, without the experience itself.</em></p>
<p>And thats why I trust more a person who approach a task carefully with budget buffers, rather than confident people who spent too much time convincing me everything will be amazing.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Getting juice out of laptop SATA/Micro connector to power up things.</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/getting-juice-out-of-laptop-satamsata-connector-to-power-up-things.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/getting-juice-out-of-laptop-satamsata-connector-to-power-up-things.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-11T18:52:16+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Long story short, I wanted to power raspberry pi through unused sata connector / bay in my thinkpad. However, it acted dead every time I've tried, with wired connector orsoldered power pins.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Long story short, I wanted to power raspberry pi through unused sata connector / bay in my thinkpad. However, it acted dead every time I've tried, with wired connector orsoldered power pins.</p>

<p>Turned out, for my thinkpads (and most likely all devices that have slimline SATA connector) to start providing power, we need to fake the presence of the device.</p>
<p>I've found that after doing some digging around documentation on google books here: <a href="https://books.google.pl/books?id=PqvNBQAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA355&amp;lpg=PA355&amp;dq=sata+device+presence+ground&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=E4RrIA9nLR&amp;sig=ACfU3U05Pm94MDOFm3K33Ni6BZG6LoowfQ&amp;hl=pl&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwir_dTT-vjjAhXhs4sKHQEkDugQ6AEwE3oECBEQAQ#v=onepage&amp;q=sata%20device%20presence%20ground&amp;f=false">[ The Essential Guide to Serial ATA and SATA Express, Page 355, Table 8.2 ]</a> and Wikipedia: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serial_ATA#Slimline_connector">[ Serial Ata: Slimline Connector ]</a> I needed to bridge first and last ( or second to last, or 5 / 6 ) pin together with resistor of 0-220ohm resistance.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--full" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/5/2019-08-10_20h46_03.png" alt="Image with informations extracted from above links." width="849" height="726">
<figcaption >Image with informations extracted from above links.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p> </p>
<p>Worth remembering. Build log of my multibay-mounted raspberry pi soon, when I get rest of the components.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What exactly is cyberpunk?</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/what-exactly-is-cyberpunk.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/what-exactly-is-cyberpunk.html</id>

        <updated>2019-08-09T10:21:59+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It's rain wet streets. It's nights like this with fog rolling in. Cars, faceless people going by, doing the things that they are doing. There's something kinds hypnotic about it. That's when I get inspired. To carry what these streets are like, what the city&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It's rain wet streets. It's nights like this with fog rolling in. Cars, faceless people going by, doing the things that they are doing. There's something kinds hypnotic about it. That's when I get inspired. To carry what these streets are like, what the city is like. The mistery, the stories, the thousands of thousands of people that you pass, that they are going by in shadows. In this wet, cold, dangerous environment.</p>
<p><img class="post__image--wide" src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/4/2019-07-16_21h30_51.png" alt="what is cyberpunk" width="1009" height="128"></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>1 test post</title>
        <author>
            <name>piro</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://propiro.github.io/1.html"/>
        <id>https://propiro.github.io/1.html</id>

        <updated>2019-07-16T21:26:16+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This post is a test. There is nothing more. Except this cat.His smile and optimism, Gone.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This post is a test. There is nothing more. Except this cat.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image" ><img src="https://propiro.github.io/media/posts/1/1550619882650.jpg" alt="his smile and optimism, gone." width="1200" height="1200">
<figcaption >His smile and optimism, Gone.</figcaption>
</figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
